Lorenz Vanthillo

CLOUD & DEVOPS ENGINEER

Kalmthout (Antwerp), Belgium

🛘 +32 496 15 38 98 | 🔀 lorenz.vanthillo@gmail.com | 🖸 lvthillo | 🚵 lvthillo | 🛅 lorenz.vanthillo | 🐚 lvthillo

Summary.

Cloud and DevOps enthusiast with almost 6 years of experience in DevOps consultancy. Passionate by AWS cloud computing, Serverless, automation and infrastructure as code. I like to contribute to open source projects, to explore new tools and write blog posts. Besides work I love to travel and learn about new cultures.

Education

College van het Eucharistisch Hart

Essen, Belgium

ASO LATIN - SCIENCES

Sep. 2006 - Jun. 2012

• Science subjects (approx. 7 hours), mathematics (4/5 hours), informatics (1 hour)

Karel de Grote - Hogeschool Antwerp

Antwerp, Belgium

PROF. BACHELOR: APPLIED INFORMATICS

Sep. 2012 - Jun. 2015

· Specialization in System & Network Engineering.

Experience_

ScanTrust Shanghai, China

DEVOPS INTERN

Mar. 2015 - May. 2015

- Setup CI/CD environment using Jenkins, Ubuntu and AWS EC2
- Configure freestyle Jenkins jobs to build, test and deploy Android, Python and Angular applications
- Create Python hosting environment using Django, Nginx, Gunicorn and Supervisor
- First experiences with Npm, Bower, BitBucket, PhantomJs, S3, Sqlite and PostgreSQL

DBM MyShopi Diegem, Belgium

CLOUD & DEVOPS ENGINEER

Diegem, Belgium Jan. 2016 - Dec. 2016

- · Creating Dockerfiles for applications
- Build fully persistent Dockerized CI/CD environment with Jenkins and Nexus
- Build OpenShift Origin environment with Ansible on EC2 instances in AWS
- Creating pods, services, deployments in OpenShift

SodexoBrussels, Belgium

DEVOPS ENGINEER

Jan. 2016 - Aug. 2016

- Developed new deployment strategy in PowerShell
- SVN to Git migrations of existing repositories
- Maintain + upgrade CI/CD server TeamCity
- AWS related challenges with Elastic Beanstalk, S3 and CloudFormation
- · Daily development support

Mazda Motor Logistics Europe

Willebroek, Belgium

CLOUD & DEVOPS ENGINEER

Put new and existing AWS resources in CloudFormation or SAM

- Use wide variety of AWS Services (+30 services)
- Bash and Python (boto3) scripting (Create new Release flow)
- Draw/develop architectural setups in AWS
- EKS PoC
- Maintain and update Jira workflows + Jira/Confluence management
- Manage and maintain Jenkins + Jenkinsfiles + implement shared library.
- Manage Artifactory Pro + perform Artifactory migration
- Write Dockerfiles + Artifactory / Docker integration

Sept. 2017 - Mar. 2021

Evolane NV Edegem, Belgium

CLOUD & DEVOPS ENGINEER

- · Working as consultant for Evolane NV
- Self-study and Docker training in my first weeks
- Organize meetups in the evening for colleagues to talk about new technologies
- Presenting about Jenkins, Kubernetes deployment strategies, AWS
- Supervising interns

UnifiedPost Group Antwerp, Belgium

Mar. 2021 - ...

Sept. 2015 - Mar. 2021

IT OPERATIONS ENGINEER

- · Working in team in a PCI-DSS compliant environment
- Monitoring with Suricata and Wazuh
- · Write Terraform for AWS infrastructure
- Use combination of Packer and Puppet to create AMI's
- Update Ansible and Ansible Galaxy configurations

Skills_

Scripting • Shell (bash), Python, PowerShell, Go (limited)

• Amazon Web Services: hands-on experience with 30+ services Cloud • GCP: GKE

• CloudFormation + SAM **Infrastructure As Code** • Terraform

• Docker + Docker-Compose

 Kubernetes **Container Orchestration**

 OpenShift 3 • ECS

• Ansible + Ansible Galaxy Chef (basic) **Automation / Devops Tools**

• Puppet (basic)

• Jenkins + Shared library

 TeamCity **Continuous Integration/Deployment** · GitLab CI/CD

> • RHEL/CentOS, Debian, Windows Server) Linux basics

• Webservers: Nginx, Apache, IIS

• SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle (basic)) Database

NoSQL (DynamoDB, MongoDB (basic))

• ElasticSearch (basic))

Source Control

BitBucket

Atlassian Stack · Jira management and workflows

Confluence

· Artifactory + AQL

· AWS Vault

ELK stack

Additional tooling

Maven

Nexus

Packer

• SonarQube

Vagrant

• Flexibility

Confidence

Soft skills

· Good listener

• Presenting experience • Self motivation

· Customer-centric

Languages • Dutch, English, French (sound knowledge)

Certifications

Docker Certified Associate (expired)

CERTIFICATE

Antwerp, Belgium

Jun. 2018 - Jun. 2020

• https://credentials.docker.com/rgmpc85u

• License Key: 11678744

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

CERTIFICATE

https://www.credly.com/earner/earned/badge/c692e153-65da-4b0c-8082-cc3d097ea19f

Eindhoven, Netherlands
Oct. 2018 - Oct. 2022

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

CERTIFICATE

• https://www.credly.com/earner/earned/badge/cdeb0071-4a36-4ba6-bb63-16b841be60e2

Eindhoven, Netherlands

Jan. 2019 - Jan. 2022

AWS Certified DevOps Engineer - Professional

CERTIFICATE

• https://www.credly.com/earner/earned/badge/5f0c3643-6eed-4431-b59c-a3f4d4a02052

Kontich, Belgium

Oct. 2019 - Oct. 2022

Certified Kubernetes Administrator

CERTIFICATE

https://www.credly.com/earner/earned/badge/14cc6268-6fc6-4182-b3e7-957fc5fb47fa

Antwerp, Belgium

May 2020 - May 2023

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

CERTIFICATE

• https://www.credly.com/earner/earned/badge/e9fdb16e-be60-40ca-975a-7e5613000da8

Antwerp, Belgium May 2020 - PRESENT

Microsoft Certified: Azure Administrator Associate

CERTIFICATE

• https://www.credly.com/earner/earned/badge/6953370d-6224-46df-82a6-597cb4f3c787

Antwerp, Belgium

May 2021 - May 2023

ITCommitment

AWS Community Builder

AWS

AWS COMMUNITY BUILDER May 2021 - PRESENT

- Approved as AWS Community Builder
- Follow AWS events and webinars
- Write blog posts about AWS
- Offer AWS support to the community

GitHub OpenSource projects GitHub

CLOUD & DEVOPS

- · OpenSource projects on GitHub
- https://github.com/lvthillo

Blog projects

Medium & dev.to

CLOUD & DEVOPS

- · Blog projects on Medium
- https://medium.com/@lvthillo
- Blog projects on dev.to
- https://dev.to/lvthillo

StackOverflow Support StackOverflow

CLOUD & DEVOPS

CLOUD & DEVOPS

- Cloud & DevOps support on StackOverflow
- Reputation of +20k
- https://stackoverflow.com/users/4525448/lvthillo?tab=profile

Re:Invent Las Vegas

• Follow talks, hands-on sessions and keynotesf

Dec. 2019